Bagi
...what, that's crazy!
...they're going to die...
...it killed my uncle...
...they say it's posessed by the devil...
Chico, hurry and hop on.
Hurry, my pocket!
Alright, we're safe!
This.. is it?
Yes sir, this is where that monster shows up, sir!
You say, every day at 11:40, it comes here?
Yes! The well fills up at 11:40. After that, it evaporates from the heat.
The monster knows this, and drinks when the water is highest!
It's 10:10. So, it's another hour and a half, eh?
Sir, what is "Bagi"? Is it a demon?
That's right. No, it's not right.
An animal.. no.. it's also a human.
Bagi is.. complicated.
She came from japan, from the same town I grew up in.
Yeah...
It was the evening of my fifteenth birthday.
Hey, crusin' this strip is bollocks, man!
Yeah! Let's get off!
All right! We're gettin' off at the next ramp!
Ryosuke... Don't jump ahead of yer senior!
Kids ride in the back!
I gotcha, boss!
Hey! Look!
It's a chick!
Hey, whatcha doin'?
Wanna have some fun!?
We'll give you a ride! Come down here!
Oh! She's runnin' away!
This'll be fun! Let's get her!
Hey, wait up! We gotta talk, girl!
Got a problem hangin' out with us?! Don't freak out, dang!
Come on!
Don't ya wanna join the party?!
You'll make a good present!
Hurry! Hurry! Hurry! Step on it!!
L-Lemme go!
But...
That hurts! Stop it!
That, was Bagi.
For some reason, it spared me alone.
Later, I found out why.
Was everyone in the gang killed?
Very badly wounded.
I didn't stick around, and ran home.
I called it home, but it was only a place to sleep, see.
Being a delinquent, I didn't go to school, either.
My dad was a crime reporter, always on the move.
My mother, being a scientist, was always shut up in her lab.
Why can't you come home?
Today is Ryosuke's fifteenth birthday!
You realize you're still his mother, right?
I mean — I can't celebrate his birthday!
Ryosuke! Where were you?!
Riding around with those slobs again, weren't you?!
If you cause an accident and make the news,
as a crime reporter, where would I stand?
I'd be a laughing stock!
You're fifteen now,
Can't you stop worrying your father?
Aren't you the one to worry about?
What was that— Aah-cha-chah!
...So, as adults, we have responsibilities!
Mom can barely come home every three months.
My job forces me to spend days away from home.
At fifteen, you can't just...
I'm away too, aren't you proud?
You're still a student, understand?
Skipping school and goofing off...
You think you can become a decent adult?
Just leave me alone, jeez.
Once I get promoted and have more time,
let's have a nice, long talk about your future.
When that be? One year? Three years? Ten years?
Yaknow, take yer time.
Don't mock me! Your father!
My god, this is the thanks I get?
I even came home from work early, for your birthday!
Really! I'm sorry I bothered you when you were so busy!
You can go back to the press.
Ryosuke!
Oh, fuck it!
Over there. In front of that empty house,
I found that chick's coat.
So, that house is the chick's hideout?
Way ta go, boss!
All right! Let's do this!
Hey, Ryo! What's wrong? Your first time, isn't it?
Alright, watch out. She could jump at us any time.
Takeshi! Go 'round back.
Gotcha!
Well?
No sign of her. Maybe ain't here.
Hey! Look! Are these dog's paw prints?
Damn big for a dog.
Maybe a bear's?
I get it now.
What?
That chick... she's got some kinda beast to protect her.
Takeshi! What's wrong?!
Bones! There are bones here!
What bones?!
I don't know, but they look like a bird's or dog's bones!
So? Don't freak out over it!
But, there're so many of em!
Ya think her bear ate 'em?
Stop yer tremblin'! Anyway, we're gonna wait for 'em.
How 'bout if we call the cops?
Get real! This is our problem.
I'm gonna find that girl and her monster...
...and give 'em a present they ain't gonna forget.
Hey... do we really have to do this?
What... Are you scared?
You sayin' you don't want to get some payback..
...on that bitch who laid us up? Eh?!
But, if she doesn't come tonight?
Then we'll get 'er tomorrow.
What?!
I don't know what, but... something touched my face!
I-I-I'm not sure if I-
I'm not lettin' anybody quit now!
Just sit there, you damn coward. Hey, Ryo!
See if she's outside.
Me... By myself?
Of course! Are you scared, or do I have to motivate you?
B-But, if she comes after me... I ain't that tough.
But you got more balls than this guy, huh?
Heh, you know, this wasn't the pussy I was looking for.
Get out.
Alright, that kid's the bait. When he's down we'll jump her and...
The bear!
Help me!
Ryo!
Ryo...
It's me... Bagi.
Bagi, y-you say?
It said it was Bagi... No way!
Yeah... it's me.
Ryo, it's been a while, hey?
It's a lie!
Bagi's not a monster like you!
Ryo, I'm surprised you don't recognize your own kitty!
It's only been nine years.
Nine... Nine years... Nine years?!
I don't know you! I swear I don't know you!
Maybe I can remind you?
See? Don't you recognize my.. scent?
Remember when we used to sleep together?..
I don't think you could forget that...
Bagi...
Yes! You didn't forget me, after all!
I'm so happy!
But, I owned Bagi when I was just a little kid!
Yeah, and I was just a little kid too.
Oh, I miss those days...
Look, Ryo! A present!
I went to see your mom, and I found it near the lab.
What? C'mon, it's a cat!
You know I like dogs better, Dad.
Don't be so picky!
Besides, cats are better, they need less care...
...like a perfect child.
This is a cat?
What else would it be?
It's pretty big! It's a weird color, too.
Its eyes aren't like a cat's, either.
I think I'll call it Bagi.
Why Bagi?
Hey, it copied me! She's really smart!
She'll eat anything, see? It's eating natto!
Golly! She wants sauce on the fish!
Bagi's reading a picture book!
Ryo, son, that cat's not going to make it.
It's dying.
She won't die! I'll make her better!
Darling — put the cat down and sleep.
No! She can't die! She's got to live!
My beautiful Bagi!
Up! I said up!
Good! Here's your treat.
Bagi! Here you go!
Father! Father!
Bagi just stood on her back feet! Hurry, come and look!
Stop screwing around.
Bagi's dancing now!
You wrote that? You... you wrote your name?
This isn't a cat!
Its expression is intelligent and its eyes are human!
And it's also huge!
Maybe it's a lion!
It could bite someone!
My horoscope said this would happen!
We'd better call the shelter!
NO!
Bagi!
Bagi! Where'd you go?!
Bagi! Please come home!
Bagi!!
Please come back...
I knew I would cause trouble for you, so I left home.
No, no, Bagi was a lot cuter!
You can't be Bagi!
Yeah, I'm Bagi. Appearances change after nine years, you know...
I've.. matured, you see?
Oh man, are you a cat? Or human?
I don't... know that either.
But, I know one thing...
..you were the only one who loved me.
I've come back, Ryo! Oh, I'm so glad to see you!
Oh! Please, don't be frightened.
Do you have a girlfriend or something?
What? N-no, I don't!
I'm a lone wolf! And why should you care?
I'm alone, too. I'm not a lone wolf though. Just.. a stray cat.
I've looked for my kind everywhere, for nine years...
...but there are none.
Why am I the only one of my kind?
Where the hell did I come from?
Bagi.. Dad found you a long time ago.
Ryo, do you.. know where I was found?
I really want to know!
I remember my dad mentioning he had stopped by the research lab that day..
He probably found you nearby.
You know the place?
Sure I do.
It's the lab my mother works at.
Is it far?
You really wanna go there?
I do.
Why?
My kind... maybe my family... I might see them there!
Ouch! Getting a bit sentimental, aren't we?
Research lab?
You mean the SuperLife Center?
Yeah, it's ten kilometers down the road.
Sorry if this sounds a bit weird...
...but uh, is there any place around with cats that can...
...stand on two feet like humans, and write and stuff?
What the hell?
What I'm saying is, I wanna know
if you heard anything about weird talking cats or something
about nine years ago.
I CAN'T THINK BACK NINE YEARS.
Boy, I can remember what happened nine years ago!
I moved from the city around then, you see.
Much quieter here, aside from that incident that first day!
Incident? What happened?
A dreadful commotion at the lab, it was such a ruckus!
What?
There were cats, dogs, chickens, all kinds of other things...
Everyone had to stay inside, it was unheard of!
Why?
Why? Well, the security in the lab came out and
killed all the escaped cats and dogs and such!
Killed them?
Sure, it was awful!
They took guns and found and shot every last one of them!
Why'd they kill them?!
Well, this was just a rumor at the time...
...but they said they weren't like normal animals!
THEY WERE MONSTERS WHO COULD TURN YOU TO STONE!
Electric fence... Damn!
Ryo...
I can jump over that and carry you.
Hang on tight! Here we go!
OK!
Augh!
Stop! It's dangerous!
Lasers! Infrared cameras are following us!
Stop! We'll be shot!
Huagh!
Look. Those lights are infrared beams.
They've set up a net of infrared lights.
Once you set it off, the lasers shoot you up.
No good. It won't even budge.
How about a window?
Get on my back.
Will you be all right?
We'll see.
Hurry, climb up!
Dang... It's sealed, too!
Wow! That was hardened glass!
Now, inside!
Is it time yet?
10:35.
So in about another hour, Bagi will come to drink this water.
There's no mistake?
No mistake! I've seen it many times.
But sir, can you really kill that monster?
The villagers don't believe you...
Bagi's a demon, so a human could never harm it.
Even if you say you were once Bagi's friend...
...If you fought with it, you'd be massacred like the rest!
Be quiet.
She's here.
No way, it's too early! it's only—
Ah! You're right!
What is it? What's wrong? It fell!
Wait, it's not Bagi! It's — a woman!
Please help... Everyone's been killed!
What?!
The village... last night... attacked! Bagi...
Where's your village?
West... Twenty kilometers.
Chico! To the bike, hurry!
Bagi killed and ate my dad.
I'm going to kill and eat her.
I don't see... how Bagi could attack women and children...
Well, it is a demon.
That's not true! Bagi's not a demon.
She's a confused... unwanted child.
Now, inside!
W-What is this place?
J-Just what kind of experiment is this?!
They're alive! They're alive...
Bagi! Threre's a head of you here too!
It is me!
Oh. Dang it, don't freak me out!!
Most likely, they're just being kept for later experiments...
...so cruel.
The goat's head is... controlling a robot!
I think I read that once in a sci-fi book...
...it called them cyborgs.
Replacing parts of one thing with parts of something else...
Looks like they're doing experiments on that, I guess.
Look, these mice.
Cyborg mice.
A cyborg bird...
Maybe... I am, too...
Heh, you don't look like any cyborg I know!
Too sexy!
But... what am I, then?
It's likely... I was also born in this laboratory.
Well, we can figure that out if we ask my mother.
My mother's on the staff in this lab.
Let's find her.
Man...! Could use a few drapes...
Don't make those footsteps! The guards will hear you!
It's not me!
It's me!
See, it's not me!
Stupid, stupid! Dang it, be quiet!
Don't do it again!
Now! Get in!
This is some kind of greenhouse.
Man, it's damp in here!
The plants are moving.
Yeah? Plants do that.
Really, they're rustling. I can hear it.
Weird they're all tropical plants. Cactuses and stuff.
You know, some botanist once said cactuses are plants of the gods.
Apparently they can detect people with supernatural powers, or something.
I heard that from my mother once, anyway.
Maybe that's why they're growing them...
And maybe making new kinds.
Hey look! These are cool, they can grab stuff—
Let go — that hurts! Quit it! I'm got no superpowers!
BAGI!
Ryo! Above!
Shit!
Hang on tight!
We did it!
Hold it!
Wups! Run for it!
Stop or we'll shoot!
Hold it!
Hey, stop right there!
There!
Dang! They shot the breaker! Where are the...
Ryo! I can see. C'mon!
Something touched my face!
Watch it! Don't shoot!
I'm calling bullshit.
No, just now two unauthorized personel were at the cactus grounds,
and gave two guards serious injuries.
But, all the entrances were closed...
The locker room's been raided!
What?!
Whitesuits are missing!
Whitesuits, you said?
Yes. They probably put them on
and are roaming the Center unimpeded.
Whatever happens, don't let them reach the P-4 level.
Sir, do you think the creature
could have come from the P-4 level?
There's no way that could happen.
The animals of the P-4 level are all accounted for.
C-Can I help you?
What are you doing at the Center?
You the President here?
Eh? T-T-T-That's right.
We're here to see Professor Ishigami.
There is no Professor Ishigami here.
Not here? Liar! She's the head researcher here!
The Professor left for South America yesterday.
South America? Where?!
She was offered a position at the Cucaracha Research Lab
in the Republic of Monica.
Something wrong with that? Introduce yourself, already!
Professor Ishigami is my mother!
What? I didn't know she was marri--..
...and who might you be?
Don't you dare!
You're able to talk?
I wanted to meet my mother and ask her
what happened at this research center nine years ago...
But now, you explain, Mr. President.
Nine years ago?
That's right. Nine years.
That time Bagi here was picked up by my father in some alley.
All right, I'll help. Just let go of me, Please.
Now talk, Mr. President.
Here at SuperLife, our brilliant minds conduct
cutting-edge research that will benefit all humanity-
Bullshit, what is she!?
Sh-It's a gene transfer experiment!
And that is...what?
Your mother, Professor Ishigami,
is the scholar of advanced genetic engineering!
To an idiot like you, gene transfer is...
combining a life form's genes with other genes...
and making new life forms.
Everything has gone perfectly except for, well, nine years ago...
Professor! In the earthquake,
P-4 has suffered serious damage!
A group of lab animals have escaped!
What's the headcount?
Fifteen animals.
Call security. Call everybody!
Eliminate the animals. Don't leave even one alive!
If genetically engineered life escapes the lab,
the ecosystem will be devastated!
Please ensure they don't survive!
This makes fourteen animals!
What kind is the last one?!
It's one of the artificially inseminated American mountain lions...
...the batch implanted with human genes...
If it grows, it will be especially intelligent and deadly!
That wasn't supposed to live! Search more!
Bagi...
I'm just a monster that shouldn't alive, aren't I?!
In this case... You were better off not knowing, right, Bagi?
Please, President Sir... if you think that all I am...
...is a creature to test some idea...
Well you're wrong! I'm alive! I'm here!
And I'm your child, whether you want me or not.
A living creature's body is made of tiny things called cells.
Hair, eyes, tongue... every part is just a groups of cells.
In the center of a cell is a core called nucleus.
If one looks at the nucleus carefully,
things called chromosomes are bunched inside.
In any living thing
is a respective number of chromosomes.
And you know what they are?!
Let's look at one a million times larger.
Kinda disgusting, really.
Inside it is a double spiral.
and in that...
are thousands of important things called genes.
These genes are passed from parent to kid,
and from kid to grandkid,
copying their bodies traits!
Because of the copying, kids are born just like their parents.
We want to know what genes control the traits!
You see, if we take out one gene...
and put it in another creature's chromosome...
...a new life form with a new body will be born!
Recently, we mixed rice, pumpkin and some other genes,
and made rice ten times bigger than normal!
("Normal" Rice vs "Newtype" Rice)
We can put human genes in animals, breed animals with human traits,
and can study the purpose of these genes!
Shut up!
I've had enough!
In short, I'm just some mongrel with no other kin, right?
That's the case.
That's... unforgivable.
She's right! Whatever your reasons,
these experiements are cruel!
Where is my mother now!?
She's at the Cucaracha Research Lab
in the Republic of Monica, by invitation!
C'mon, let's go see her.
I'd recommend against that.
I do understand how you feel, but as a member of this center...
I have to put your down.
We will dissect you,
and after we study your innards and brain, we'll freeze your body.
Intelligent or not, It's the proper way to deal with a lab animal!
Stop! Listen to me!
Don't try to convince me, boy!
What the fuck?
Pick up that pen.
Write what I say.
Republic of Monica, care of Cucaracha Research Lab,
Professor Yohko Ishigami.
I have found the remaining living animal escaped from nine years ago,
and am sending it to you now.
Your son, Ryosuke, will accompany it.
Please follow the Republican government's procedures.
There, sign your name.
Now, order your people! Get us a plane to that country!
Bagi, you're...
I'm sorry...
...but if I didn't, we would've been shot.
Was that hypnotism?
Something like that.
Man, you're terrifying.
Ryo, please don't be scared of me.
I didn't ask to be able to do these things.
Are you going to hypnotize me, too?
Why would I do that?
You're my only friend in the whole world.
I'll tell your mother... my mother...
to stop her horrible research and cruel experiments.
If she doesn't listen...
If she doesn't listen, what will you do?
You don't...intend to kill my mother, do you?
...I won't.
You promise?
I promise....
She's my mother!
She left me to become a lab monster, but she's still my mom!
I'll talk to her as a son...
...I'll convince her what she's doing is wrong!
She'll stop the experiments, and we'll finally have a family again!
Um, I left my inhaler in the luggage down below...
Don't be long, it's quite cold down there.
It's okay!
And don't go snooping in luggage...
Why'd you let the kid inside? We had a deal!
BAGI!
Fuck!
Fucking cactuses!
I'll kill you!
Let go! Let go damn it!
Bagi... Hang in there!
R-Ryo... look o-out...
It's okay now. You're safe now...
Someone must have shipped the lab's cactuses,
with the hope of killing you!
Precisely.
It was requested by your sponsor that the creature die in-route.
If you hadn't interfered, the cacti would have done that job for me!
I shouldn't have bothered with First Class...
Well, enjoy the rest of the trip!
We're gonna die!
I saw this in a movie once!
Idiot! Look, it's a kilometer to the ground!
It's 800 meters!
700 meters!
Shut up and give me that cloth! Hurry!
It's 500 meters now!
Quit counting, and pass me those cacti!
Grab my tail! Hang on tight and don't let go!
Okay?!
Where's the ground?
What's below us?
Lots of rocks!
Can you see a soft place to land?
Yeah, there's a gully ahead!
Then we're jumping! Hang on!
BAGI!
Ryo! You're finally awake!
Oh, I'm so glad!
What was that thing?
The wound hasn't closed yet! You shouldn't move for a while.
If I lick it, it will get better.
Cut it out... How long will you lick it?
Another three days.
Three whole days?
This is the fourth day.
I've kept licking it while you were unconscious.
The whole time?
At first it was amazing—the blood!
This forest...are we in the Republic of Monica?
No, but we seem to be close to it.
In that case—let's go, right now.
We can't.
The Republic has armed guards—you'd soon be shot.
Then what do we do?!
You're saying we hide in this jungle forever?
Hey, c-cut it out!
I'll get something to eat. Wait there, okay?
B-Ba-Ba-B-Ba-Ba-Bagi-Bagi!— BAGI!
GIVE US BACK OUR DINNER!
Eat up. You'll feel a lot better
I'm a snake-boy!
With a bad joke like that, you're fine now, I guess.
Yeah, with us as a pair, we can make it somehow.
We'll go to the lab, persuade my mother and take her back to Japan.
Like when I was little, we'll start over, as a family.
When she meets you I'm sure she'll see.
And what'll happen to me?
Just leave me behind in this counry?
Of course not! You'll live with us! Like back then.
You'll care for me, like a pet?
No way! As a sister!
Really?!
But there's a condition. Trim your claws, OK?
When you get sentimental, it gets kinda painful.
I'll do anything! I'll trim my whiskers if you want!
Wait, I want to show you something!
Well?
I made it from dead birds while you slept!
Does it look good on me?
Y-Yeah, sure it does. You look like a fashion model.
Thanks! I'll try and dance for you, OK?
Ah! Those're the aerobics you saw on TV as a kid, right?
Yeah Ryo! It's a gift for you!
Whoa, a squall!
Hey, that's enough! You're soaked!
I don't care! I'm happy!
Hey, cut it out! That's my shirt!
I'm washing it!
Your tail destroys windows!
It also cleans whites.
Wait a sec—I hear something.
It's a car, I think.
Aw, friggin' animals.
W-What?
It worked.
Bagi's hypnosis, eh?
Don't be scared of me, she said, but...
She scares me a lot now and then!
Stop!
You in the truck, stop!
Stop right there!
Get out.
Everyone, out.
Over there, now.
We know there are rebel guerrillas hiding around here.
We have reason to believe you are a part of those rebels.
So, we'll investigate. Show me proof you're with the circus!
This American lion performs tricks.
Bagi, help.
Tricks, you say? Fine, let's see it do this...
Pyrotechnics?!
Follow the ball!
A flaming coil.
Pass through it, and I'll let you go.
What? That's impossible, come on!
There are thirty meters of it!
Jump in, and she'll be burned to death!
She's doing it!
If she doesn't, I'll have you executed as guerrillas!
Bagi, you'll die.
We'll see.
She did it! She made it!
What are you—?!
Mom...
Ryo, son...
It really is you.
You're awake, I'm so glad!
Is this is the Cucaracha Research Lab?
That's right.
Damn, we made it. Our goal at last!
It's like a dream. You were shipped here,
and when I heard that "Ishigami" was written on your shirt,
I jumped with surprise!
Mom, where's Bagi— Ow!
You mustn't move yet. Lie down.
Where did Bagi go? Where is she?
Bagi? Oh, the lab animal, right?
Thank you for delivering it. We'll soon dissect the specimen.
What did you say?!
Ahg, ow...
How could you do that?! She's my friend!
If you kill her, why I'll...
Ryo...
It was a research subject to further our knowledge.
It can't fit in anywhere on the planet.
We must dispose of it.
If something happens to Bagi,
even if you're my mother, I will kill you!
What!? My little Ryo—! You've changed, haven't you...?
Whose fault is that?!
Okay, Mom...
Stop this stupid research right now, and lets return to Japan!
We can be a family, like we were before! Dad and I miss you!
Can't be done. I was contracted by this country's government to work here.
Besides, our current research will be an important breakthrough
in helping humanity's poorest! I can't just abandon that!
Shut up!
Can't you think of anything besides your GOD DAMNED RESEARCH?!
I think you need some rest.
If you study hard, maybe you'll see why I'm right.
Mirror, mirror, on the wall...
Reveal your cats to me, and all!
Tranquilizer darts are a bitch, hey, Bagi?
To make sure you don't exert yourself, we've glued you down.
Nor will your "hypnosis" affect me through the TV screen.
You can barely understand what I'm saying, can you?
We've never had a subject retain intelligence after such extreme stress...
...but it seems you're quite the clever girl
to hold out as long as you have!
I'll have your heart frozen and take it back to Japan as a present for my colleage!
If you can still speak, do so. Your brain is...well...
I just want to say I'm sorry, that you lived...
...I didn't mean for you to suffer.
Don't... do this... research...
please... Mother...
What! You don't know how many lives we've saved!
Thousands! Millions!
If we keep going, I can save everyone!
Your selfishness is disgusting!
And I'm not your Mother!
Stop the research!.. How could it stop?...
Your Excellency, we are honored to have you come
all this way to visit this Cucaracha Research Lab.
Professor Ishigami, arrived from Japan with a noble cause, I see.
The new kinds of large servings you developed...
to the starving people of our country...
shall be a great salvation!
This way, please.
These are the new servings we just gathered.
This is rice?
Seems almost like bread.
We still haven't tested them yet.
Just in case, please allow us to feed them to animals before you try them.
You mean they're not safe?
Excellency, everything made by gene transfer is a new species.
Therefore, we must find out exactly what it is.
But, I heard in Japan it was safe.
Yes... But since then,
we have improved the gene arrangement a little.
The government has been fighting rebel guerrillas for ten years now.
If we feed these servings to the starving public,
our reputation will improve!
Emergency! The animals that ate the rice—
What's the meaning of this?
What happened?
The rice we just made contained a very strong poison.
A poison?! No... There's no way...
All right, back to your room, kid.
I'm Semmen Bond. Your babysitter.
Watch.
Just sit still for an hour,
and you won't be shot up like that.
Why an hour?
One hour's when this critter Bagi's dealt with.
Sit tight 'til then.
Bagi... is going to be killed, in an hour?!
Now, back in your room, kid.
No!
Don't throw a fit.
I'm saving Bagi no matter what!
Stop me if you can! Shoot if you want!
I'll save Bagi even if I'm dead!
Don't show off.
Put away that speech.
Say, kid, wanna test your luck?
Bet on this coin.
Win and I'll let you go.
Lose and, it's a pity, but I'll shoot you.
Heads or tails.
Heads!
It's heads. Kid, you lucked out.
Go on, it's a promise.
Hey, that's the toilet!
You're helpless. This way.
Follow me.
Below here.
Professor Ishigami, it's nothing to mourn about!
Everyone makes mistakes.
Excellency...
In trying to make God's blessing, I've made food for the devil!
I can't continue... this research anymore.
I'll have this horrible food disposed of.
No, no, you don't need to throw them away.
Indeed, it's useful as it is.
Excellency, it is rice that contains a strong poison.
Anyone who eats it will die.
Anyone will die? Precisely.
If we feed this rice to the guerrilla rebels who oppose our government...
They'll be wiped out where they stand!
What on Earth?
That's not all!
We feed it to the writers who voice discontent with the government and clean them out!
There's still more!
Let's feed it to the scum in neighboring countries that support the guerrillas!
I'll sweep them all away! Let's wipe them out!
Oooh, what a good idea!
Our nation is secured... We can be of a world power!
Your Excellency intends to use it to kill...?
Yes, it's a weapon!
It'll be a splendid weapon!
Now, Professor Ishigami, please start mass-producing this rice at once!
I must refuse to that.
R-Refuse?!
I have researched to create new foods
to help those suffering with hunger.
I cannot create poisonous life for murder!
You mean to oppose me? You mean to defy my orders?
Oh— This is the first time I ever heard such a reply!
To defy me is unforgivable!
Make the rice like I told you to!
I am a scientist. I cannot assist in murder.
I'm returning to Japan.
Returning, you say!
I suggest you try setting foot outside this lab.
Those attack dogs will tear your body to pieces!
Bagi!
Bagi, it's me!
I'll save you now.
Hang on... Dang it...
You're glued down! The bastards...
Dang it... It's no good. If I pull you off, your fur will tear.
Mr. Bond, tell me how to free her.
Stop acting spoiled. Give it up and go to your room.
Please! I'm a good boy, so tell me!
It's no trouble for you!
You're not going to tell me?! Then let's fight! C'mon!
Don't piss me off for real.
Fine, let's bet with this.
Win and I'll tell you. Lose and go to your room. Which is it?
T-Tails!
What a pain. You won.
Hey, this is the glue. This is the glue remover.
Bagi, we have no time.
R-R-Ryo... thank you.
O-Okay, okay. Bagi, stand up.
W-What's wrong?
R-Ryo... I c-can't stand, so...
Can't talk w...
Okay, you don't need to stand. We'll still run away.
That's not happening.
Who told you to run away? Playtime's over now.
Go to your room.
You've gotta be kidding!
Only an idiot would come this far and not run away!
I just humored you. Was it fun for you, kid?
Dang... You were making fun of us?!
You're a sucker to catch on now.
You be careful I don't use this. Go to your room.
You bastard, now you've done it!
Way to go, Bagi! Let's go!
I'll find us some wheels! You look for my mother!
What is this place?
An elevator!
Ryo. Ryo!
What? Crap! It's going up!
What is that?
Stop it.
What is this thing?
Maybe it's Kikuchiyo.
Hey! This is that... That...
My mother—I mean, Professor Ishigami is on what floor?
What have I been doing all this time?
I believed I could make anything with the power of science.
But in the end, I made something this horrible.
I can't go back from here...
Professor Ishigami, it's the President's order.
We're taking the rice ball.
We'll take things over from here.
Please hand that over.
You're not getting it. Tell that to the President.
If you defy his orders, you'll regret it.
Leave this place!
It's here.
Bring out my mother, no matter what.
I'm telling you just in case, but...
Don't bite my mother, or claw her.
Let's meet at the main entrance.
W-What is it?
Ryo... please.
Just once... please stroke... my throat.
Eh? Like this?
Yes... Wonderful...
I'll be killed soon.
But before that, I must take this plastic-hardened poisonous rice away from here.
If this rice is ever cultivated, it'll be too late.
There's no knowing how many billions will die.
They're here. The attack dogs, no doubt.
Bagi!
The garage.
Yes.
It's gasoline!
It'll explode!
I'm in luck! There are bikes here. Two of them, even!
Planning to escape?
Prepare yourself, boy!
Now, fight!
I'll make you this blade's rust.
Running away?! You coward!
Cool it, you war freak!
Hold it!
I did it!
That's Bagi!
Bagi!
Bagi, over here! I'm over here!
Mom... Mom!
Awful...
You've been bitten to shreds.
Bagi is...
Bagi?
Mom! Mom!
Don't die!
Mom!
Did Bagi bite you?
Dang it... When she promised that much!
Shoot... Heck if I'll die!
Bagi, you bastard...
You bit Mom to death and ran off, didn't you?!
You really pulled a big one.
Kid... You show some promise.
Did you come after me?
Heck, no. I got fired.
Because I let you get away.
That's not my fault.
I already know that.
My, aren't we pissed off?
Bagi got my mother.
That dang cat... She hated my mother.
She bit her to death and ran off.
My, my. It's like being bitten by your pet dog.
Bagi's not a pet dog! She's my friend.
I trusted her, but she...
The dead ain't comin' back.
But anyway, what will you do?
I'll find Bagi and kill her.
I'll get her back for betraying me!
You're getting revenge?
Yeah. I'll beat her dead!
Can you do it, kid?
Bond, I'm asking you. Teach me how to use a gun.
Teach you how to use a gun?
Yeah... If I'm as good as you, I can kill Bagi, can't I?
For how much?
I don't have any money.
No chance in heck.
Please, I'm begging you!
Until I get Bagi, I'm not returning to Japan!
I don't mind a girl cryin' on my arm, but you...
What the heck... Lose, and give it up.
Heads or tails.
Tails.
Aw, heck, I'm dang unlucky.
Come here.
We eat first. Don't worry, I'll pay.
Five years later
Sorry.
Pardon me.
Mind if I sit there?
There are other places to sit, aren't there?
I want to sit in front of you.
It's hot and stuffy. No thanks.
We are the government—
Ishigami, Ryo... We are from the government public safety department.
Have you come to arrest me?
Well, indeed, you have ruined a large laboratory of ours...
Doing great damage.
But, it's been five years since then. Situations have changed.
We have come to ask a favor from you.
We know you are a free-willed gunman.
We want you to take care of a certain creature.
That creature's name is—
That creature's name is Bagi.
It's this kinda critter.
It's a dangerous monster.
Lately... It's been attacking villages here and there,
and has bitten dozens of people to death.
Up to now, many hunters have gone after Bagi,
but all wound up half dead.
You're the only one who can beat that monster.
If you kill Bagi, we'll pay you ten thousand dollars.
How is it?
Furthermore, for you to be able to return to Japan...
we'll include a passport, visa, and all the other documents!
Or what would you say? Since Bagi was once your pet,
are you going to say you can't kill it?
Shut up!
Well, looks like the deal's off. Adios, señor.
Hold it. Do you know where this Bagi is?
There's a kid who knows. But...
To find out from him, we need to borrow your skill.
No way in heck!
I know where Bagi is. But I'm not telling anyone!
That's a problem, Chico.
No way, no way! I'm never telling!
Bagi killed my dad.
So I'm going to get Bagi.
Go home, now!
What are your conditions?
How about splitting the reward?
Just watch!
Wow! What a skill!
If you take me on and win, I'll show you where Bagi is.
Are you going to, sir?
Yeah.
If my rock hits, it'll crush your nose.
Yah, bravo, bravo!
I lost, sir. It's a promise.
I'll show you the way.
You'll be useful. Prepare me a motorcycle, and a rifle.
My dad was walking down the street when Bagi bit him to death.
I should've thrown a rock and killed it.
What a sight. The village's wiped out.
It's horrible. Too horrible!
Bagi's a demon, after all.
Hold it.
Something's wrong. These prints don't seem to be of one creature.
It seems there are two or three, at least.
No way, there couldn't be two or three Bagis.
Even little babies are bitten to death.
Poor things.
Chico, careful!
You all right? Your wound?
This isn't Bagi.
Really?
This is... a normal American lion.
Besides, there were four of them.
The ones attacking the villages weren't Bagi.
Ah! This is...!
This is... This is the string of dad's bolas!
I learned it from my dad.
My dad fought this one and got bitten to death!
See!
It's my dad's!
This is, maybe... It may be a big mistake.
The monster attacking people and villages, and Bagi...
are different!
Those are military helicopters.
They're chasing us.
No... I'd say they're following us.
Why? Why would they follow us?
I'm finally figuring out what's going on.
A dirty trick, you bastards.
Señor Ryo Ishigami, thank you for your help.
Your job is over. Could you let us take over from here?
You bastards...
You suckered me into thinking I'd fight the monster and used me as a guide,
so you could hunt it down with your army.
We'll pay you the reward, as promised.
You've no problems then, right?
We'll finish off Bagi on our own. Get out of here.
This was arranged from the beginning, wasn't it?
Exactly. That kid wouldn't show us where Bagi was.
So we used you and had the kid show you.
And so it happens we followed you.
Bagi didn't turn out to be a man-eater!
If that critter eats people or not, I have nothing to do with it.
Then what's with this overblown chase?
Bagi ran off with a rice ball that's a deadly poisonous weapon.
I have to retrieve the rice ball and report to the President.
Now, my soldier friends, go and attack.
All right! Draw out the creature!
What's wrong? Is it gone?
Hey, what's wrong? C'mon and answer me!
Is it there or not?!
The traitors!
A-An attack!
Shoot...
You dared to kill my mother.
I've been waiting for this day.
We'll settle this.
C'mon! C'mon and fight, Bagi!
If you won't, I'll make you come!
W-What?
Sir! Something's shining on Bagi's chest! She's wearing something!
Shoot!
Look out!
Where are you hiding?
Bagi!
Coward! Come on out!
Sir!
Rifle!
Dang it...
The bike! The bike! She's aiming for it!
Finally, the last blow?
The Indians encircle the cavalry and tighten the ring,
and attack at once.
It means you can kill me in any way you want now.
It's my end. But you're dying with me, Bagi!
Sir... You did it! You did it, didn't you!
I thought you were done for!
I thought so too, but Bagi hesitated...
...from killing me.
This is it. This was shining really bright.
Let me see. This is...
the pendant my mother wore.
What?
My mother's last words.
I am having Bagi escape with a rice ball.
I have instructed her to bury the rice ball in a mountain, hiding it.
Most of her intelligence has vanished,
but she must have understood my request.
Should he know I betrayed him,
the President no doubt will have me killed by attack dogs.
Bagi will return to the wild.
Probably, she will end her life in the mountains.
Life forms like Bagi and the rice ball should not be made by humans.
I have been a bad scientist, and a bad mother.
Ryosuke, I'm sorry. Take care... Bagi too.
How horrible...
Bagi didn't kill my mother.
My mother let her go.
Why didn't you say so? Why did you keep it to yourself, Bagi?!
If you had said anything, I would've taken you back to Japan.
You'd have become family and we'd have lived together like I promised.
Bagi... Please come back!
Let's go to Japan together!
Please don't die, Bagi!
Bagi!
Sir! We're in trouble!
Bagi we brought here, and left out back,
disappeared this morning!
What?!
I'm sure we left her here, and covered her up, right?
See, she's gone.
Somebody took away the body.
Say... What are those?
Paw prints!
They're Bagi's paw prints!
No way! I mean, Bagi died for sure.
So, she came back!
The prints disappear past that thicket.
Bagi was alive... and she went to the mountains.
That's it. That's what happened, Chico!
I wonder why she went back.
That doesn't matter. Bagi, live through it.
Bagi, live all you can. I'm praying for it!
She won't show up in front of humans again, probably.
It's better that way.
Translation: Owen Henderson, Machiko Yanagawa
Trans. Materials: Noel Tominack & Machiko Yanagawa